Hello everyone.
大家好。
So today we are going to continue our discussion about file systems.
所以今天我们将继续讨论文件系统。
And in particular, we are going to go through a few examples to see how some of the most
而且特别是，我们将通过几个例子来看看一些最常见的情况。
popular file systems in the past have been implemented.
过去实施过许多流行的文件系统。
Just to recall, these are the main data structures which are maintained by a file system.
只是为了回顾一下，这些是文件系统维护的主要数据结构。
First of all, we are going to have directory structures, which is, as you know, it's a
首先，我们将拥有目录结构，就像你知道的那样，它是一个
radical.
激进的。
And here you are going to use a file path to locate a particular file in this directory
在这里，你将使用文件路径来定位该目录中的特定文件。
structure and an entering the directory structures associate the file with an inumber.
结构和进入目录结构将文件与i节点相关联。
An inumber is an index in an index structure called file header structure.
一个inumber是一个称为文件头结构的索引结构中的索引。
And this index points to what is called an inode.
这个索引指向的是一个被称为inode的东西。
And the inode contains all the information which is relevant to the file and which helps
to locate and access the file on the file system. The inode stores metadata such as the file's permissions, owner, size, timestamps, and pointers to the actual data blocks on the disk.
the operating system to locate the data for that file on the disk.
操作系统会在磁盘上定位该文件的数据。
So the first case we are going to go over, it's FAT.
所以我们要讨论的第一个案例是FAT。
FAT stands for file allocation table.
FAT代表文件分配表。
And this was the first file system employed by Microsoft Disk Operating System, which
并且这是微软磁盘操作系统所采用的第一个文件系统，它
is the first operating system released by Microsoft all the way in 1977.
是的，微软在1977年发布了他们的第一个操作系统。
And it's still quite used today, despite after what, after 50, 44 years.
尽管已经过去了50年，但它至今仍然被广泛使用。
And the FAT file system is quite simple.
而FAT文件系统非常简单。
So first of all, what you have here on the right, it's blocks on the disk and the disk
首先，你在右边看到的是磁盘上的块和磁盘。
blocks.
块。
And you have a file for each file you have where the block is located.
你每个文件都有一个文件，其中记录了块的位置。
Each file has a bunch of blocks.
每个文件都有一堆块。
And like you say, for file system 31, this is where the disks are located.
就像你所说的，对于文件系统31，这是磁盘所在的地方。
And then you need to maintain in the FAT table a pointer or the identity of where the disks,
然后你需要在FAT表中维护一个指针或者标识符，指示磁盘的位置。
the blocks are located, therefore to the index of that block.
这些块的位置，因此是该块的索引。
So the disk block, you can think about of an array of blocks.
所以磁盘块，你可以把它想象成一个块的数组。
Each block has an identifier.
每个区块都有一个标识符。
Typically it's a logical identifier, which is mapped then on a physical identifier to
通常它是一个逻辑标识符，然后映射到一个物理标识符上。
the disk.
磁盘。
And the FAT maintains a mapping between the files and the list of blocks identifiers,
并且FAT维护着文件与块标识符列表之间的映射关系。
logical identifiers.
逻辑标识符。
So how does FAT maintain that?
那么FAT是如何维护这一点的呢？
It's again, this is maintained in the inode.
这是再次提到的，这是在inode中维护的。
The inode is indexed by the inumber.
inode是由inumber索引的。
Let's assume that the file number here is 31.
让我们假设这里的文件编号是31。
And the FAT is just basically a linked list.
而FAT基本上就是一个链表。
Each entry in the linked list corresponds to a block of a file.
链表中的每个条目对应文件的一个块。
And each entry will maintain the index of a block and then a pointer to the next entry,
每个条目将保持一个块的索引，然后指向下一个条目的指针。
which points to the next block.
指向下一个块的指针。
So here, assume that you are going to have in three blocks in this file, 0, 1, and 2,
所以在这里，假设你将在这个文件中有三个块，0、1和2。
you have three corresponding entries in the FAT table.
你在FAT表中有三个对应的条目。
And each entry will have an index to a corresponding block and then a pointer to the next entry,
每个条目都会有一个指向相应块的索引，然后是指向下一个条目的指针。
to the next entry corresponding to the next block in the file.
到文件中对应下一个块的下一个条目。
Also as you know, when I am opening a file, another important data I need is basically
另外，正如你所知，当我打开一个文件时，我基本上需要的另一项重要数据是什么？
the offset.
偏移量。
So what is the current position in the file?
那么文件当前的位置是什么？
The current position in the file here is given by a tuple.
当前文件中的位置由一个元组给出。
The first tuple is a block in the file.
第一个元组是文件中的一个块。
And the second part of the tuple, it's basically the offset within that block.
第二部分元组，基本上是该块内的偏移量。
Yeah.
是的。
So the question is, where does x, the second element of the 2x tuple, comes into the place?
所以问题是，x，即2x元组的第二个元素，放在哪个位置？
Again, x, it's offset within the block 2 in this case.
再次，x，在这种情况下，它在块2内偏移。
So that's why in order to access the data here from block 2, you start from block 0,
所以为了从块2访问这里的数据，你需要从块0开始。
then you have to follow the linked list to block 1, then to block 2, and now block 2,
然后你需要按照链表的顺序访问块1，然后是块2，现在是块2。
this is a block I care about.
这是我关心的一个区块。
Now I can retrieve block 2, and then I'm going to the offset x within the block 2.
现在我可以检索块2，然后我要在块2中的偏移量x处进行操作。
So it's a very simple technique.
所以这是一个非常简单的技巧。
So now you read the block 2 in the memory and then you access offset x within that block.
所以现在你读取内存中的块2，然后访问该块内的偏移量x。
So again, it's a collection of blocks, and each entry in this linked list, in the fat
所以，再次说，它是一个块的集合，这个链表中的每个条目，在FAT中。
linked list, corresponds to a block.
链表，对应一个块。
And the file number, it's basically the file number for simplicity in the case of fat,
文件号，基本上是为了方便起见，在FAT案例中的文件号。
it's exactly the index of the root block in the file.
这是文件中根块的索引位置。
So in this case, 31, it's also the index of the root block on the disk.
所以在这种情况下，31也是磁盘上根块的索引。
Okay, so what about, obviously, what about free blocks?
好的，那么，显然，那么空闲块呢？
So you need free blocks in order, obviously, to extend the file.
所以你需要有连续的空闲块，显然，才能扩展文件。
Remember that the file expands as you write more in the file.
请记住，随着您在文件中写入更多内容，文件会扩大。
So there are four new files you need to follow.
所以有四个新文件你需要跟进。
If you want to write a new file, you need to look at, to find these free blocks.
如果你想要写一个新文件，你需要查找这些空闲块。
The free blocks, typically there are two ways to manage these free blocks.
这些空闲块，通常有两种管理方法。
One is to have a list of free blocks.
一个方法是拥有一个免费区块的列表。
The other one, you can have a bitmap of free blocks.
另外一个，你可以有一个空闲块的位图。
So basically, in this bitmap case, you have for each block, you have a bit, one or zero,
所以基本上，在这个位图案例中，对于每个块，你有一个位，要么是1，要么是0。
one if it's, that block is not free, it's used by a file, zero if it's free.
如果是被使用的话，返回1，表示该块不可用，如果是空闲的话，返回0。
Okay, so this is how you find it.
好的，这是你找到它的方法。
In this particular case, for instance, if you are going to write, if the file for now
在这个特定的情况下，例如，如果你要写的话，暂时的文件是什么。
has only three blocks, and you want to write more data, like in this case, I want to write
只有三个块，而你想写更多的数据，就像在这个例子中，我想写入
in file 71 in block C, so this means the fourth block, then what happens again, the file,
在第71个文件的C块中，这意味着第四个块，然后会发生什么，文件。
the operating system, the file system expands the file and finds them by finding a new block
操作系统中的文件系统会扩展文件并通过查找新的数据块来找到它们。
in the empty list and then allocating that block and now that block is part of the file
在空列表中分配该块，现在该块是文件的一部分。
and it's also part of the linked list of all the blocks which belong to that file.
并且它也是属于该文件的所有块的链表的一部分。
So now, what is fast thought?
那么，现在，什么是快速思考？
So it's again, this is persistent storage, all these modifications needs to persist after
所以，这是持久存储，所有这些修改都需要在之后持久保存。
I am going, I write a file, for instance, I modify the file, and then I close the application
我要走了，我写了一个文件，比如说，我修改了这个文件，然后关闭了应用程序。
because next time when I open the application and I want to read the files, I want my changes
因为下次我打开应用程序并且想要阅读文件时，我希望我的更改能够保留。
to be reflected.
被反映。
So therefore, by default, this, all this information is a fact, not only the data, but also the
所以，因此，默认情况下，这些所有的信息都是事实，不仅仅是数据，还包括其他的内容。
metadata, it has to be on persistent restored in this and the obvious place to restore it
元数据，它必须在此处进行持久性恢复，并且恢复它的明显位置。
is on the disk.
在磁盘上。
How do you format a disk?
你如何格式化磁盘？
Do you know what formatting a disk means for people?
你知道对于人们来说，格式化磁盘是什么意思吗？
So, formatting meaning, you know, I want to make the disk as new, right?
所以，格式化的意思是，你知道的，我想要将磁盘恢复成新的状态，对吗？
I want to basically erase everything and the way you do it is basically you zero the blocks
我想基本上抹掉所有东西，而你要做的就是基本上将块清零。
and in the fact table, you mark everything being free.
在事实表中，你将所有东西都标记为免费。
There is a question here from Gilbert.
这里有一个来自Gilbert的问题。
Do the blocks not have to be in order in the linked list?
链表中的块是否不需要按顺序排列？
So I'm afraid I don't understand that question.
所以，我恐怕不明白那个问题。
Can you be more precise Gilbert about this question?
你能更准确地解释一下这个问题吗，Gilbert？
So are you asking that because the linked list is fundamentally ordered.
所以你是在问这个问题是因为链表在本质上是有序的。
Ah, like block three is before the block two.
啊，就像第三个块在第二个块之前一样。
That's exactly why we have a linked list because when you are going to read from a block, we
这就是为什么我们使用链表的原因，因为当你要从一个块中读取数据时，我们可以通过链表快速找到该块。
are going to go along the linked list.
你将要沿着链表进行遍历。
Okay.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like to have translated.
So that's the main point, right?
那就是主要的观点，对吗？
So in this particular case, we are going, again, if you follow the linked list, the
所以在这个特定的情况下，我们会再次按照链表的顺序进行，如果你跟着链表的话，那么...
linked list will link the blocks in the order, you know, it's all written.
链表将按顺序链接这些块，你知道的，它都已经写好了。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like me to translate.
They are appended to the file.
它们被追加到文件中。
That's exactly why I need a linked list.
这正是我需要链表的原因。
To preserve that, to store that order.
为了保护那个，保存那个秩序。
What happens if we try to insert something in the middle of a file for FAT?
如果我们尝试在FAT文件中间插入内容会发生什么？
Do we insert a new block into the linked list or is there something more clever?
我们是将一个新的块插入到链表中，还是有更巧妙的方法？
Well, if you insert, you see in any file system and most file systems actually, you cannot
嗯，如果你插入，你会在任何文件系统中看到，实际上大多数文件系统都是如此，你无法
insert a block in the middle, right?
在中间插入一个块，对吗？
Because from the file system, think about what is the interface.
因为从文件系统的角度来看，我们需要思考接口是什么。
You can just write to the block.
你可以直接写到这个区块。
So or read from the, sorry, you write through the file and read from the file.
所以，或者从中读取，抱歉，你通过文件写入并从文件中读取。
If you write from the file, if you write in a place where already contains data, you override
如果你从文件中写入，如果你在已经包含数据的位置写入，你会覆盖掉原有的数据。
that data, right?
那个数据，对吗？
So you write in an already existing block, right?
所以你是在一个已经存在的区块中写作，对吗？
And if you write at the end of the file, then if you run out of existing, the block at the
末尾写入文件时，如果已经用完现有的块，则会在文件末尾添加一个新的块。
end of the file, you are going to add a new block.
文件末尾，你将要添加一个新的块。
So you are going to expand the file.
所以你打算扩展这个文件。
Good question.
好问题。
How to quick format a disk?
如何快速格式化磁盘？
You can mark all the FAT entries to free.
你可以将所有的FAT条目标记为可用。
And this can be easily implemented.
这可以很容易地实现。
The main point here, it's again, it's like you can actually, and there are two ways to
这里的主要观点是，再次强调，实际上你可以，而且有两种方法可以。
format it.
格式化它。
And again, format meanings in, it just, you want to have the disk as new.
再次，格式化的意思是将其恢复为新的状态，就像你想要将硬盘变成新的一样。
Now if you just remove all the information in the FAT without doing anything with the
现在，如果你只是删除FAT中的所有信息而不对其进行任何操作，
disk blocks, the disk block still remains, you know, you don't zero them.
磁盘块，磁盘块仍然存在，你知道的，你不会将它们清零。
Then from the point of view of the operating of the file system, the disk is free.
那么从文件系统的角度来看，磁盘是空闲的。
You can allocate everything because you removed, you just mark all the FAT entries being free,
你可以分配所有的空间，因为你已经删除了它们，只需将所有的FAT条目标记为可用。
right?
对吗？
So you are going to allocate from the previous blocks, which you'll return for a different
所以你打算从之前的块中分配，然后将其返回给不同的地方。
file, so just override them.
文件，所以只需覆盖它们。
No problem.
没问题。
Now, obviously this is not a hard format because it maintains the information from the previous
现在，显然这不是一个固定的格式，因为它保留了之前的信息。
files.
文件。
And typically when people format, they also want to erase this information for security
通常，当人们进行格式化时，他们也希望出于安全考虑擦除这些信息。
reasons.
原因。
So you need to be careful about what kind of format is going to happen on your formatted
所以你需要注意你的格式化会发生什么样的格式。
disk.
磁盘。
If you care about the information from your previous files to not be visible.
如果您关心之前文件中的信息不可见。
Again, for instance, you hand down, you hand back your computer to your employee or something
再举个例子，比如你把你的电脑交给你的员工，或者其他类似的情况。
like that.
那样。
The FAT directory is again, it's like, you know, directory you have to remember, you
FAT目录又来了，就像你知道的那样，这是一个你必须记住的目录。
have this and it topples.
这个东西会倒下来。
One is a file name.
一个是文件名。
The first part is a file name.
第一部分是一个文件名。
The second one is a file number.
第二个是文件编号。
And here is a FAT we also have, it's a linked list, right?
这里还有一个FAT，它是一个链表，对吗？
It's like we know.
就像我们知道的那样。
And all the directory, you know, what you see in a directory, which is basically a list
和所有的目录，你知道，在一个目录中所看到的，基本上就是一个列表。
of names, what happens here, you are going to have each of these, what you see entering
名字，这里发生了什么，你将会拥有每一个这些，你所看到的进入的东西。
this directory is going to be linked, all of them, you know, in a linked list.
这个目录将会被链接，所有的目录，你知道的，都会以链表的形式链接起来。
If you remove a file, then you are going to update the pointers so that you are going
如果你删除一个文件，那么你将会更新指针，以便你可以
to step over that file, which was over that entry, which was deleted.
跨过那个被删除的入口上方的文件。
So that's how you have here.
这就是你在这里的方式。
So it's very simple.
所以很简单。
So one, there are a few things about the FAT directory, which is worth mention.
首先，关于FAT目录有几个值得一提的事情。
It's where do you have the attributes, the attributes for a file?
你在哪里拥有文件的属性？
The attributes for a file is like protection and permission attributes.
文件的属性包括保护和权限属性。
You know, who has access to the file to read it, to write it, to execute that file, if
你知道，谁有权访问该文件以阅读、写入、执行该文件，如果
it's a binary file.
这是一个二进制文件。
And in the FAT, these attributes are maintained here in the directory.
在FAT中，这些属性在目录中被保留。
Like we'll see in other file systems, these attributes are associated with the file itself.
就像我们在其他文件系统中看到的那样，这些属性与文件本身相关联。
The other question, which in general is, it's an important question for all the file systems.
另一个问题，总的来说，对于所有的文件系统来说都是一个重要的问题。
Where do you find the root?
你在哪里找到这个根？
Where do you start from?
你从哪里开始？
Right?
对吗？
To get the root.
获取根目录。
If I give you a file name, you need to go and get the root directory and then go through
如果我给你一个文件名，你需要去获取根目录，然后遍历。
the path names in that directory to find the particular file name and then the I number
在那个目录中查找特定文件名的路径名称，然后找到I号码。
for the file.
文件。
And typically this root, it's a well defined place on the disk.
通常情况下，这个根目录是磁盘上一个明确定义的位置。
For instance, in the case of FAT, it's block two.
例如，在FAT的情况下，它是第二个块。
So what else here?
这里还有什么别的？
Obviously, because this is maintaining a link list, then in order to read a directory and
显然，因为这是在维护一个链表，所以为了读取一个目录并且
to display the content of the directory, you need to go over this link list.
要显示目录的内容，你需要遍历这个链接列表。
You need also to go over, which is called "conf" defined because when you do a display,
你还需要查看一下，这被称为“conf”定义，因为当你执行显示操作时，
like all the entries in a directory, you want to display all the files in the directory.
像目录中的所有条目一样，您想要显示目录中的所有文件。
But when you want to find a file in a directory, you still need to have to go over this link
但是当你想在一个目录中找到一个文件时，你仍然需要点击这个链接。
list, which can be expensive.
清单，可能会很昂贵。
Any questions?
有任何问题吗？
Okay, so here are a few questions.
好的，下面是几个问题。
So suppose you start with a file number, the file number is everyone, like in our previous
所以假设你从一个文件号开始，文件号是每个人的，就像我们之前的一样。
example.
例子。
And here you see also yellow is you have a file too.
这里你也可以看到黄色，你也有一个文件。
Let's see, what is the time to find a block?
让我们看看，找到一个区块需要多长时间？
What do you need to find a block?
你需要找到一个区块的条件是什么？
Yes, you take this, it's O(n) where n is the number of blocks.
是的，你拿着这个，它的时间复杂度是O(n)，其中n是块的数量。
Actually, in this case, you say root then traverse to the desired number.
实际上，在这种情况下，你需要先找到根节点，然后遍历到所需的数字。
Here you already have the file number, the 31.
这里已经有了文件号，是31号。
So you don't need to do the directory traversal.
所以你不需要进行目录遍历。
But yes, this is correct and Gilbert.
但是，是的，这是正确的，而且是Gilbert。
So basically in this particular case, you need, it's a linear search, right?
所以基本上在这个特定的情况下，你需要的是线性搜索，对吗？
You need to find a particular block.
你需要找到一个特定的区块。
You need to follow the pointers in the link list.
你需要按照链表中的指针进行操作。
And everyone knows that link list to find something in a link list is linear search
而且每个人都知道，在链表中查找某个元素是线性搜索。
in the ER file.
在ER文件中。
So what is a block layout for files?
文件的块布局是什么意思？
It was a previous question, do they need to be contiguous?
这是之前的问题，它们需要连续吗？
Not...
不...
Yes, it's correct.
是的，没错。
Actually, they don't need to be contiguous, they can be random because then we are going
实际上，它们不需要连续，它们可以是随机的，因为这样我们就可以
to have our link list in the fat table to maintain the order, the logical order of the
为了保持顺序，我们需要将我们的链接列表放在FAT表中，以维护逻辑顺序。
blocks, which provides you a lot of flexibility about where to allocate the blocks and which
块，这为您提供了很大的灵活性，可以自由选择在哪里分配块以及使用哪些块。
is good.
是好的。
Sequential access.
顺序访问。
What do you think about sequential access?
你对顺序访问有什么看法？
Is that fast, slow?
那是快的，还是慢的？
Yes.
是的。
The directories are linked lists also are presented in the fat in the...
目录也是以链表的形式在FAT中表示的...
And yes, they are also linked lists, but with directories is a linked list between the entries
是的，它们也是链表，但是在目录中，条目之间是通过链表连接的。
in the directories.
在目录中。
Here for the files themselves, you have the linked list basically between the blocks of
这里是关于文件本身的内容，你可以在块之间使用链表来实现。
that file.
那个文件。
Now the answer to the question sequential access can be somewhat slow because we need
现在问题的答案是，顺序访问可能会有些慢，因为我们需要
to linearly scan for every access because we do not have a guaranteed order.
因为我们没有保证的顺序，所以需要线性扫描每个访问。
It's correct.
没错。
So the sequential access can be slow because if you look at how block 0, 1 and 3 are located
所以顺序访问可能会很慢，因为如果你看一下块0、1和3的位置
here, block 0 and 1 are consecutive.
这里，块0和1是连续的。
And because they are consecutive, you do not need to incur a seek latency or rotation latency
因为它们是连续的，所以您不需要承担寻道延迟或旋转延迟。
if to go from block 0 to block 1.
如果要从区块0前往区块1。
But now to go from block 1 to block 2, you have to incur a seek latency or rotation latency.
但是现在要从块1跳转到块2，你必须承受寻道延迟或旋转延迟。
As you know, this is huge.
正如你所知，这是巨大的。
So yes, you have a lot of flexibility where to put the blocks on the disk, but if you
所以是的，你在磁盘上放置块的位置有很大的灵活性，但是如果你
are not careful and you put them randomly, then it's going to hurt your access time.
如果你不小心并且随意放置它们，那么它会影响你的访问时间。
Random access.
随机访问。
How is random access?
随机访问如何？
Yes, it's even slower since you have to incur, you need to sequentially search for the block
是的，由于需要承担额外的开销，所以速度会更慢，你需要按顺序搜索块。
which contains the data you want to read or write.
其中包含您想要读取或写入的数据。
So it's quite slow.
所以它相当慢。
Fragmentation.
碎片化。
How is fragmentation?
碎片化的情况如何？
Yes, fragmentation is pretty good.
是的，碎片化很好。
It's not much fragmentation because remember you can put the blocks anywhere.
这并不会造成太多的碎片化，因为请记住，你可以将这些块放在任何地方。
So if you have just some free blocks, you are going to get it.
所以如果你只有一些空闲时间，你就会去做它。
No problem.
没问题。
It's okay.
没关系。
It's going to hurt your performance, but you can have very, you know, your fragmentation
这会影响你的表现，但你可以有很多，你知道的，你的碎片化。
will be very low.
将会非常低。
Small files.
小文件。
Is this a vision for small files?
这是一个针对小文件的设想吗？
Remember, what if you know, if the file fits in one block is very efficient.
记住，如果你知道文件适合一个块的话，效率会很高。
It's very good.
非常好。
If a file fits only in one block.
如果一个文件只能放在一个块中。
Why?
为什么？
Because you already, the file number, it's indexed into the block, the first block.
因为你已经有了文件号，它已经被索引到了第一个块中。
So you find it immediately.
所以你立刻找到了。
Right?
对吗？
As you have, you know, more blocks in the file, then it becomes more efficient for the
随着文件中的块数增加，它变得更加高效。
reason I mentioned.
我提到的原因。
Right?
对吗？
We mentioned.
我们提到了。
Yes, it's even more inefficient is again, because the blocks can be layout, their layout
是的，这样做甚至更加低效，因为块可以进行布局，它们的布局
on the disk can end up being random.
在磁盘上的位置可能是随机的。
And then you pay a lot of sick time, rotation, latency to read and write from the file.
然后你需要支付很多病假时间、轮班和读写文件的延迟。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you need to be translated.
So this is fat, right?
这是脂肪，对吗？
Very simple and very influential.
非常简单而且非常有影响力。
Right?
对吗？
This was for many, many years, for decades, this was a file system for personal computers.
这个是很多年来，几十年来，个人电脑的文件系统。
Because obviously 90% of the personal computers were running Microsoft operating system.
因为显然90%的个人电脑都在运行微软操作系统。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
Now, let's switch gears and talk about Unix file system.
现在，让我们转换话题，谈谈Unix文件系统。
And the Unix file system, this is Berkeley standard distribution, 4.1 is what we are
而Unix文件系统，这是伯克利标准发行版，4.1是我们所使用的。
looking to now.
我现在正在寻找。
And yes, this is a part of your heritage.
是的，这是你遗产的一部分。
And the similar Linux today has very similar file structure.
而今天的类似Linux也有非常相似的文件结构。
So it's again, a hugely influential file system.
所以它又是一个极具影响力的文件系统。
The file number or I number is again, it's an index into an array of inodes.
文件号或I号再次是指向inode数组的索引。
And the inodes corresponds to a file, right?
是的，inode对应一个文件。
Inodes contains the indexes to the blocks on the disk.
索引节点（Inodes）包含了磁盘上块的索引。
And in this case, it also contains other metadata associated with a file.
而在这种情况下，它还包含与文件相关的其他元数据。
It's pretty good for both little and large files.
这对于小文件和大文件都非常好。
And all the assumes that still all the blocks have the same, are the same size.
并且所有的假设都是基于所有的区块仍然具有相同的大小。
And the trees, what you are going to see is asymmetrical.
而且树木，你将会看到的是不对称的。
So here is how it looks like.
这是它的外观。
So you have an inode array, the file number, it's an index in this array.
所以你有一个inode数组，文件号是它在这个数组中的索引。
The inode in this array is basically, this is the inode data structure.
这个数组中的inode基本上就是inode数据结构。
The first part, there are a bunch of attributes.
第一部分，有很多属性。
Like for instance, nine basic control bits you have here.
例如，这里有九个基本控制位。
You have typically owner or user, group and others.
你通常有拥有者或用户、组和其他人。
So it's basically whether the owner of the file, and for each of them, you have three
所以基本上是关于文件的所有者，对于每个文件，你有三个选项。
bits, read, write, execute.
位，读取，写入，执行。
So for owner of the file, for the group and for others, right?
是的，对于文件的所有者、组和其他人，对吗？
Basically for everyone else.
基本上是为了其他所有人。
And typically, obviously the owner has the most rights than the group and then everyone
通常情况下，显然业主拥有比群体更多的权利，然后是每个人。
else.
其他。
And also you have a few other bits, which basically you can execute only at the owner
而且你还有一些其他的东西，基本上只能在所有者处执行。
permission rather than users and to execute at the group's permission.
权限而不是用户，并且在组的权限下执行。
So it's again, it's pretty classic.
所以，这又是一个非常经典的例子。
And the more interesting part is after this.
而更有趣的部分在此之后。
Okay.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
But remember this permission bits and information is associated with the inode, with a file
但请记住，这些权限位和信息与inode（索引节点）和文件相关联。
in this case.
在这种情况下。
In the case of FAD, it was this information was maintained in the directory.
在FAD的情况下，这些信息是保存在目录中的。
And then you have 13 other entries in this inode structure.
然后在这个inode结构中，你还有其他13个条目。
Each entry points to a block.
每个条目指向一个块。
The first 10 entries are called, each of them, they are pointing to one block.
前10个条目分别被称为，它们每个都指向一个块。
The 11th entry points is called indirect pointer and points to a block, which each element
第11个入口点被称为间接指针，它指向一个块，该块包含每个元素。
is a block.
是一个块。
It's a pointer to a real block.
这是一个指向真实块的指针。
And you have double indirection pointers where this points to a block, which is full of pointers
而且你还有双重间接指针，其中这个指针指向一个充满指针的块。
or each pointer points to another block, which is full of pointers to finally two blocks.
每个指针指向另一个块，该块中充满了指向最终两个块的指针。
And then you have triple indirection pointers, which is again going three levels.
然后你有三级间接指针，再次进行三级引用。
So in this case, you have, if you have four kilobytes blocks, it's efficient.
所以在这种情况下，如果你有四千八百字节的块，效率会更高。
You have, here you have, yeah, sorry.
你有，这里有，是的，抱歉。
I said the first, the direct number of direct pointers was 10.
我说的是第一个，直接指针的直接数量是10。
It's actually, sorry, it's 12.
实际上，抱歉，是12点。
And then you have three other ones, one for indirect, double indirect and triple indirect.
然后你还有另外三个，一个用于间接引用，一个用于双重间接引用，还有一个用于三重间接引用。
Okay, so you have 12.
好的，所以你有12个。
And if you have 12 pointers, this means that if you have 4k blocks, you can have, you can
而且如果你有12个指针，这意味着如果你有4k个块，你可以有，你可以...
store using only direct pointers, you can store 48 kilobytes.
仅使用直接指针存储，您可以存储48千字节。
And if you remember from last time, when you're looking at these results from this paper,
如果你还记得上次的话
which are looking at the statistics of the length of the file system or the size of the
哪些是在查看文件系统的长度统计或大小的？
file systems, in that paper, in the plots we presented last time, we are seeing that
文件系统，在那篇论文中，在我们上次展示的图表中，我们正在看到...
most of the files are small files.
大部分文件都是小文件。
So therefore, for most of the files, you are using only the direct pointers.
所以，对于大多数文件，你只使用直接指针。
And then for the bigger files, you are going to use the indirect pointers, double indirect
然后对于较大的文件，你将使用间接指针、双重间接指针。
pointers and triple indirect pointers.
指针和三级间接指针。
So just to give you a sense, you can get, for double indirect pointers, you can get
所以只是为了让你有个概念，对于双重间接指针，你可以获得的是
to four megabytes.
四兆字节。
Why?
为什么？
Because in this particular case, it's again, this pointer here is a certain pointer.
因为在这个特定的情况下，这里的this指针是一个特定的指针。
It points you to one block.
它指向了一个区块。
A block has four kilobytes.
一个块有四千字节。
Each pointer in this case is four bytes.
每个指针在这种情况下是四个字节。
So therefore, in a block you have 1024 pointers.
所以，在一个块中你有1024个指针。
Each of these pointers points to a block.
每个指针都指向一个块。
A block has four kilobytes.
一个块有四千字节。
So now you have 1024 times four, you have four kilobytes, you have four megabytes.
所以现在你有1024乘以四，你有四千字节，你有四兆字节。
This is level two.
这是第二级。
It's one indirect.
这是一个间接的。
Then double indirect is going to add another layer and it's basically you have four gigabytes.
然后双重间接将增加另一层，基本上你会有四个千兆字节。
And then for if you have triple indirect pointers, you have four terabytes.
然后，如果你有三级间接指针，你会有四个太字节。
So it's a lot of storage.
所以这是很大的存储空间。
Now the disadvantage for this one, what is the disadvantage with going with indirect,
现在谈谈这个方案的缺点，选择间接方式有什么不利之处？
double indirect and triple indirect blocks?
双间接块和三间接块？
What is the disadvantage here?
这里有什么缺点？
Yes, longer access times.
是的，访问时间更长。
Because right now, if I'm going to have, if I'm going to go to this, you know, the first
因为现在，如果我要去参加这个，你知道的，第一个...
level pointers, I'm going to get the inode and then from inode I get the pointers, all
级别指针，我要获取inode，然后从inode获取指针，全部获取。
the pointers to the block.
指向该块的指针。
So I have another access to get to the data, one extra access.
所以我有另一种方式来获取数据，额外的一种方式。
If I'm going to have triple indirect in order to get to these data blocks, I have to get
如果我要通过三级间接才能访问这些数据块，我必须先获取
one other access to get the first level block, which contains pointers at the first level.
另一种获取第一级块的方法是，该块包含第一级的指针。
Then another pointer, another, I need to access another, they get another block at the second
然后又一个指针，再一个，我需要访问另一个，它们在第二个位置获取另一个块。
level to contain against pointers and another block at the third level contains again pointers.
第一层级包含指针和另一个块，第三层级的另一个块再次包含指针。
And finally, I'm going to get to the data block, to the real block.
最后，我要进入数据块，到达真正的块。
So here I have for each of these levels, I have an extra access.
所以对于每个级别，我都有额外的访问权限。
On the other hand, it's pretty cool design, right?
另一方面，这个设计非常酷，对吧？
Because for the small blocks, you know, it's pretty efficient.
因为对于小块来说，你知道的，它非常高效。
Small block less than 48 kilobytes.
小块小于48千字节。
All these pointers here are to data blocks.
这里的所有指针都指向数据块。
At the same time, you can store huge files, like up to four terabytes in this design.
同时，您可以在这个设计中存储大型文件，比如高达四个TB的文件。
Yeah, it's a question here.
是的，这里有一个问题。
This seems really similar to page tables.
这似乎与页表非常相似。
Do file systems have the equivalent of super pages or huge pages?
文件系统是否有超级页面或大页面的等效物？
It's very similar to the files, you know, it's similar to the page table in some respects,
这与文件非常相似，你知道，在某些方面与页面表相似，
right?
对吗？
One is that the unit of allocation, it's a block, it's a page.
其中一个是分配的单位，它是一个块，是一个页面。
It's also they are connected, right?
是的，它们也是相互连接的，对吗？
Because the reason for which you have pages when we do demand paging is why?
因为我们进行需求分页时，你有页面的原因是什么？
Because these pages need to be stored eventually on the disk when they are evicted, right?
因为当这些页面被驱逐时，它们最终需要存储在磁盘上，对吗？
And they need to be read from the disk.
并且它们需要从磁盘上读取。
And the unit, again, it has to be the same unit, it's a block, right?
而且单位，再次强调，必须是相同的单位，是一个块，对吗？
So block and the pages are basically the same unit.
所以“block”和“页面”基本上是同一个单位。
Otherwise, it makes things much more complicated.
否则，事情会变得更加复杂。
And you'll see towards the end of the lecture, hopefully we can get there, where you'll see
在讲座的最后部分，希望我们能够到达那里，你会看到...
the similarity even more because we are going to talk about memory map files.
相似性更加明显，因为我们将要讨论内存映射文件。
So then you are going to map the files into memory, and then you'll see even more of the
所以你打算将文件映射到内存中，然后你会看到更多的内容。
similarity.
相似性。
So in terms of file system having the equivalent of super pages of huge pages, you do have
所以在文件系统中，是否有类似于超级页面或大页面的等效物？
that not in Unix, but you do have that in the Windows, the more modern Windows file
那在Unix中没有，但在Windows中有，更现代的Windows文件中有。
system, Microsoft file system.
系统，微软文件系统。
And in that case, you have what is called extents, what we are going to learn later
在这种情况下，你所说的是“范围”，我们稍后会学到。
in this lecture in which the blocks can have variable size.
在这个讲座中，这些块可以具有可变大小。
Great questions.
很棒的问题。
So let's take an example here.
那么让我们来举个例子。
So right now, and that's why I was a little, you know, in this particular, it's a different
所以现在，这就是为什么我有点，在这个特定的情况下，它是不同的。
example and we here assume that each block is one kilobyte.
例子中我们假设每个块是一千字节。
And we assume that there are 10 direct pointers and in indirect block, so these 10 direct
指针和间接块中有10个直接指针。
pointers, so directly you can access only one kilobyte, 10 times, 10 kilobytes files.
指针，所以直接你只能访问一个千字节，10次，10千字节的文件。
And then because you have only one kilobyte, if each entry, each point there is four bytes,
然后因为你只有一个千字节，如果每个条目，每个点都占据四个字节，
then you have only 25, six indirect blocks at the first level.
那么你只有25个一级间接块。
And then you have 256 power 2 double indirect blocks and 256 power 3 triple indirect blocks.
然后你有256的2次方个双间接块和256的3次方个三间接块。
So that's kind of the layout in this case.
所以这种情况下就是这种布局。
And now the question is that how many accesses you need, how many accesses to get to the
现在的问题是你需要多少个访问权限，需要多少个访问权限才能到达目标。
block 20 string?
你是指"block 20 string"吗？
Assume the file is everything is open.
假设文件是完全开放的。
Now I'm just one process block 20 string.
现在我只是一个进程块20个字符串。
How many accesses?
多少次访问？
So is this 23 in a direct pointers part?
这个是直接指针部分的第23个吗？
It's not right because I have only 10.
这不对，因为我只有10个。
Is 23 in a, yeah, yes, 23 will be in the single indirect block.
23将位于单个间接块中。
So you need two accesses, right?
所以你需要两个访问权限，对吗？
You need the first access to get to the root of the first level indirect blocks.
你需要首次访问才能到达第一级间接块的根。
And then from here, once you get there, you are going to read the data block.
然后从这里开始，一旦你到达那里，你将读取数据块。
What about block five?
第五个区块怎么样？
Block five is in the first 10.
第五个区块在前十个位置。
So you are going to have only one access to read the data block number five.
所以你只能有一个访问权限来读取数据块编号为五的数据。
Blocks are 340.
区块数为340。
That's 340 fits in the first level indirect blocks.
这在一级间接块中可以容纳340个。
Does it fit?
适合吗？
How many you have there?
你那里有多少个？
You have 2556 plus 10, which are direct.
你有2556加上10，这些是直接的。
It's only 266 indirect blocks or direct blocks.
只有266个间接块或直接块。
So therefore, it has to be in double indirect.
所以，它必须是双重间接的。
So then you are going to have how many accesses?
那么你将会有多少个访问权限？
Again, one access per level, each level.
每个层级只有一次访问机会，每个层级都是如此。
So you need, you have double.
所以你需要，你有两倍。
So for each level, you need one access or two and the third one for access to the data.
所以每个级别，你需要一个或两个访问权限，第三个用于访问数据。
Okay, some announcements again.
好的，再次进行一些公告。
Many congrats for finishing the second midterm.
非常祝贺你完成了第二次期中考试。
We are making progress here.
我们这里正在取得进展。
Block five has been released.
第五个区块已发布。
It will be due on Monday, November 22nd.
它将于11月22日星期一到期。
And the project two, obviously now is due on Sunday.
而且，项目二显然是在星期日截止。
So hopefully everyone here is in a good state with that project.
希望大家对这个项目都处于良好的状态。
If not, please feel free to ask any questions.
如果有任何问题，请随时提问。
We are here to help you.
我们在这里帮助你。
Okay, so that was the initial file system in Unix 4.1.
好的，那么这就是Unix 4.1中的初始文件系统。
Now people, obviously after they use it for a while, they figure out there are some limitations
现在人们，显然在使用一段时间后，他们会发现一些限制。
and they try to address these limitations.
他们试图解决这些限制。
And the address is limitation in what is called Berkeley FAST file system, FFS, which is BSD
地址限制在所谓的伯克利快速文件系统（FFS）中，该系统是BSD的一部分。
0.4.2.
Right?
对吗？
This was released in '84, so still a long time ago.
这是在84年发布的，所以还是很久以前的事情。
And it's very similar with 4.1.
它与4.1非常相似。
The differences are that while in 4.1, typically the block size of one kilobyte, in 4.2, one
差异在于，在4.1中，通常块大小为1千字节，而在4.2中，一个块的大小为
to four kilobytes.
四千字节。
Why?
为什么？
Because obviously the discovery has increased in size.
因为显然这个发现的规模增加了。
And it's a very good paper.
这是一篇非常好的论文。
I recommend you to read it in the reading material.
我建议你在阅读材料中阅读它。
If not, you can search on the web and you can get it, but it's very interesting.
如果没有的话，你可以在网上搜索，你可以找到，但是这非常有趣。
And there are a bunch of optimization and we are going to go briefly through these optimizations
还有一系列的优化措施，我们将简要介绍这些优化措施。
and compare with 4.1.
并与4.1版本进行比较。
And so let me go through, I'm not going to go now through this list.
所以让我来看一下，我现在不会逐个列举这个清单。
I'm going while I am going to explain this optimization, but the middle things about,
我在进行这个优化的同时，会解释一下其中的中间过程。
first of all, let's talk about what are the motivation?
首先，让我们谈谈什么是动机？
What are the problems with the file systems in Unix BSD 4.1?
Unix BSD 4.1的文件系统存在哪些问题？
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
So, the one thing is that the file system, the FAD table and all of these inode data
所以，一个重要的事情是文件系统、FAD表和所有这些inode数据。
structures, right?
结构，对吗？
They were in a fixed disk, in the fixed place on the disk.
它们被存储在固定的磁盘上，位于磁盘上的固定位置。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
So, and the problem with that, if you have all these inodes on the disk in one place,
所以，如果你把所有这些索引节点都放在磁盘的一个地方，那么问题就来了，
then it's very likely that they are going to be far from most of the data blocks, right?
那么很有可能它们会远离大部分数据块，对吗？
The data blocks are all over, obviously, and the inodes are only at the edge.
数据块分散在各处，而索引节点只存在于边缘。
In order to access the data blocks, you need the information from the inode of that particular
为了访问数据块，你需要从该特定inode中获取信息。
file, right?
是的，文件，对吗？
So, you need to read an inode and you are almost guaranteed that the place where the
所以，你需要读取一个inode，并且几乎可以保证inode所在的位置
inode was stored on the disk is far away from where the data is located on the disk.
inode被存储在磁盘上，与数据在磁盘上的位置相距很远。
So it's seek time, you are going to pay for the seek time.
所以这是寻道时间，你将支付寻道时间的费用。
The other thing is reliability.
另一个问题是可靠性。
If somehow the outer edges, tracks of the disk are destroyed because sometimes when
如果不知何故，磁盘的外缘和磁道被损坏了，因为有时当
some of the failures happen is that when you have a power outage and the disk was rotating
一些故障发生的原因是当你遇到停电时，磁盘仍在旋转。
and sometimes the heads were kind of scratching the disk in that particular case.
有时候头部在那种情况下会有点刮到磁盘。
Then if you lose this kind of the inode information, you lost everything.
那么如果你丢失了这种inode信息，你就会失去一切。
So that's a problem.
那是一个问题。
The other thing, it's hard to allocate for performance, right?
另外一件事，很难为性能分配，对吧？
Because in Unix, most writes, in many writes are by appending.
因为在Unix中，大多数写操作，很多都是追加写入。
It's again, when you write, either you write to existing block because what the existing
这是再次发生的情况，当你写作时，要么你写给已经存在的区块，因为已经存在的区块是什么。
data is, so you override the data.
数据是如此重要，所以你要覆盖这些数据。
But if you append, in many cases, you just append to a file, then you are going to add
但是如果你追加，很多情况下，你只是追加到一个文件中，然后你将会添加什么。
new blocks.
新的方块。
And the problem here is that you want to allocate in some sense, obviously you want to allocate
这里的问题是你想要在某种程度上进行分配，显然你想要分配。
blocks which are contiguous, right?
连续的块，对吗？
But that's kind of what's difficult.
但这就是困难所在。
In the case of 4.1, you need to be able to do 4.1, you have a link list for the free
在4.1的情况下，你需要能够做4.1，你有一个用于空闲的链表。
blocks like in the FAT table.
块，就像在FAT表中一样。
And then the way you allocate, you go through this list and well, you allocate always the
然后你分配的方式是，你遍历这个列表，然后，嗯，你总是分配
first block which is available.
第一个可用的区块。
But going through the list of the free blocks, all these blocks can be all over the place.
但是浏览免费区块的列表时，所有这些区块可能散落在各个地方。
So what have they done?
那么他们做了什么呢？
So here what have they done?
Basically, they define this kind of block groups.
基本上，他们定义了这种类型的区块组。
So the tracks which are nearby are in the same block and correspondingly also they define
因此，附近的轨道位于同一个区块中，相应地它们也定义了
the cylinder group.
圆柱体组。
All the blocks which fall under block groups, which are falling under the head, the drive
所有属于区块组的区块，都是属于头部的驱动下掉的。
heads on all the platters are in the same cylinder.
所有盘子上的头都在同一个圆筒中。
You imagine a cylinder which are going to contain all these data blocks which are overlay
你可以想象一个圆柱体，它将包含所有这些覆盖的数据块。
one over another.
一个在另一个之上。
So right now, then instead of having these inodes and only at the edge, stored at the
所以现在，不再只有这些inode存储在边缘位置，而是存储在整个系统中。
edge of the disk, you are associating these inodes to the files, the inodes which for
磁盘的边缘，你正在将这些索引节点与文件关联起来，这些索引节点是用来描述文件的。
the files whose data is stored in the same block are also in the same block.
数据存储在同一块中的文件也在同一块中。
So you see, this is the inodes information for the files which are stored in block group
所以你看，这是存储在块组中的文件的i节点信息。
one.
一。
And these are the inodes information for the files with data, it's in block group two.
这些是具有数据的文件的i节点信息，它们位于块组二。
Furthermore, instead of maintaining the available free blocks in a list, you have a bitmap.
此外，你可以使用位图来代替维护一个可用空闲块的列表。
And I'll tell you, I'll show you next what you can do if you have a bitmap.
我会告诉你，接下来我会展示如果你有一个位图可以做什么。
Right?
对吗？
But this is what it is.
但这就是现实。
Now, in terms of performance, if you have this kind of layout now because the inodes
现在，就性能而言，如果您现在有这种布局，是因为i节点的原因。
are in the same block groups with the files, with the corresponding files, what do I gain
与文件在同一块组中的是什么，有哪些对应的文件，我能得到什么？
here?
这里吗？
What do I save here in terms of performance?
在性能方面，我在这里能节省什么？
What is the big deal about this?
这有什么大不了的？
Again, for a file to access a file, I need to get its inode and then I need to access
再次，要访问一个文件，我需要获取它的inode，然后才能访问。
its data.
它的数据。
Because once I get the inode, I have the information or the blocks of the file are located, I'm
因为一旦我获取到inode，我就能知道文件的信息或者文件块的位置。
going to read or write.
要读或写。
So that is a big deal about this layout.
这个布局有什么了不起的地方。
If the inode is near the file blocks, then it will be much faster to read, especially
如果inode靠近文件块，那么读取速度会更快，尤其是
for small files.
对于小文件。
This is good.
这很好。
It's a sick time.
这是一个糟糕的时期。
It's exactly, Alison.
没错，Alison。
And it's basically the sick time will be smaller, will be much lower.
而且基本上病假时间会更短，会大大降低。
Because the sick time, it's about how far the two tracks are from each other.
因为病假时间，这是关于两条轨道之间有多远的问题。
This is a sick time, it is given by.
这是一个糟糕的时期，它是由外界给予的。
And now the blocks are on tracks which are closer together.
现在积木放在距离更近的轨道上。
So this is what it is.
这就是它的样子。
It's not only that I read the inode and I'm going to read these files, but also all the
不仅仅是我读取了inode并将要读取这些文件，而且还有所有的
blocks of the file are in a block group.
文件的块位于一个块组中。
If they're in a block group, then going from one block to another, even if they are not
如果他们在一个街区组里，那么即使他们不在同一个街区，也可以从一个街区走到另一个街区。
contiguous, the sick time is going to be low.
连续的，病假时间会很少。
Also, here, one thing which I didn't mention is that the inode for files and the entire
此外，这里还有一件我没有提到的事情，那就是文件和整个目录的inode。
directories with the files, the file system tries to put them on the same cylinder.
当文件系统将文件与目录放在一起时，它会尝试将它们放在同一个柱面上。
So on different corresponding blocks on different platter of the disk.
因此，在磁盘的不同盘片上的不同对应块上。
So it's again to minimize the sick time.
所以这又是为了减少病假时间。
In this case, going to do an alias from directory, all the information is within the same cylinder.
在这种情况下，将从目录中创建一个别名，所有的信息都在同一个柱面内。
OK, we discussed about this data block metadata and free space are within each block.
好的，我们讨论了这个数据块的元数据和空闲空间都在每个块内部。
A voice huge sick time between user data and system structures.
用户数据和系统结构之间存在一个巨大的病态时间。
And you also put the directory, like I mentioned, and these files in the common block group.
你还要将目录，就像我之前提到的那样，以及这些文件放在公共块组中。
So basically, you try to preserve some locality between the metadata of the files and the
所以基本上，你试图在文件的元数据和
data blocks of the files by being careful how you store them on the disk.
通过谨慎地存储文件的数据块在磁盘上，可以提高效率。
But I try to be close to each other.
但是我努力亲近彼此。
Like I mentioned, the list of free block allocation, here we use Bitmap.
就像我之前提到的，这里我们使用位图来表示免费块分配的列表。
Before, we used List.
以前，我们使用的是列表。
And by using Bitmap, you can actually avoid some fragmentation.
通过使用位图，你实际上可以避免一些碎片化。
One important thing which is true both for the Unix file systems in Unix DSD 4.1 and
在Unix DSD 4.1中，对于Unix文件系统来说，有一件重要的事情是真实的。
4.2 is that you need to keep some 10%, 20% of free space always.
4.2 是指你需要始终保留10%到20%的可用空间。
Because if you don't have any kind of free space, really, really you have no freedom
因为如果你没有任何形式的自由空间，真的，真的你就没有自由了。
about where to allocate the new blocks.
关于在哪里分配新的数据块。
And they are going to become pretty very random.
他们将变得非常随机。
So the performance of the disk will slow down to a crawl.
所以磁盘的性能会变得非常缓慢。
But I'll say a few more words about that.
但是我会再多说几句关于那个的话。
But now let's see what is the big difference and what is the advantage of maintaining a
但是现在让我们看看维护的重大区别和优势是什么。
Bitmap for the free blocks instead of linked lists.
位图用于表示空闲块，而不是链表。
So here is the difference.
这里是不同之处。
So and we'll go over the summary here.
好的，我们将在这里概述一下。
So here is the difference.
所以这里有一个区别。
So here is a Bitmap.
这是一个位图。
And the dark shades, each rectangle, it's a corresponds to a block, each square corresponds
而那些深色的阴影，每个矩形都对应一个区块，每个方块都对应一个
to a block.
到一个街区。
And the shaded one represents blocks which are in use.
而阴影部分代表正在使用的区块。
And the white ones represent free blocks.
而白色的代表空闲块。
So here is a very nice characteristic.
这里有一个非常好的特点。
So let's say that I am starting to add, to expand the file, and I'm going to allocate
所以假设我现在开始添加内容，扩展文件，并且我要分配空间。
new blocks.
新的方块。
I have to allocate new blocks.
我需要分配新的块。
So what I'm going to do here, I'm going to go through this Bitmap.
那么我在这里要做的是，我要遍历这个位图。
I'm going to start reading from the beginning.
我要从头开始阅读。
And whenever I'm going to see a free block, I'm going to allocate it.
每当我要查看一个空闲块时，我都会分配它。
So this one, the blue one, starts the one which has been allocated.
所以这个，蓝色的那个，开始分配的那个。
So so far, so good.
到目前为止，一切都还不错。
Again, it's like I'm going to allocate what I see and encounter first.
再说一遍，就好像我要先分配我所看到和遇到的东西。
So these blocks actually, in terms of the location, can be quite random if they are
那么这些区块实际上在位置上可以相当随机，如果它们是
not one near each other.
不要一个靠近另一个。
However, when I am going to start allocating, the more I allocate to a file, the more I'm
然而，当我准备开始分配时，我分配给一个文件的越多，我就越
going to start looking for bigger gaps, for more contiguous regions.
要开始寻找更大的间隙，以便找到更多连续的区域。
And I think that's basically the key.
我认为这基本上就是关键。
So initially, I am allocating as I find these blocks available, empty.
所以起初，我会根据可用的、空闲的块进行分配。
But then after a while, when I start to allocate more and more new blocks to a file, I'm starting
但是过了一段时间，当我开始给一个文件分配越来越多的新块时，我开始
to look more and more for contiguous blocks.
越来越多地寻找相邻的区块。
And because I have a Bitmap, it's much easier to look for contiguous blocks because I know
而且由于我有一个位图，所以查找连续的块会更容易，因为我知道
I just look at the Bitmap.
我只是看了一下位图。
In the case of the linked list, it's much harder because I need to pop up to go from
在链表的情况下，这要困难得多，因为我需要弹出来从...开始。
one to another entry with a linked list.
一个到另一个的入口，使用链表。
And with a linked list, really, I'm going to look in the order in which I am going to
使用链表，实际上，我会按照我要的顺序进行查找。
see to find in the linked list the free blocks.
在链表中查找空闲块。
Does it make sense?
这有意义吗？
So the PLDR here is that if I have a Bitmap, then it's much easier for me to identify contiguous
PLDR stands for "Point of Least Drama" in this context. It means that if you have a Bitmap, it will be much easier for you to identify contiguous areas.
regions of free blocks.
自由块的区域。
It's as simple as that.
就是这么简单。
More efficient.
更高效。
And then as I have larger and larger files which allocate more and more blocks, I'm going
然后随着我拥有越来越大的文件，分配越来越多的块，我就会...
to start using and allocate more of these contiguous blocks.
开始使用并分配更多的这些连续块。
Yeah, it's a Bitmap.
是的，它是一个位图。
So the question here, the blocks here are in an array rather than a linked list.
所以问题在于，这里的块是以数组的形式而不是链表的形式存在的。
Yes, it's a Bitmap.
是的，它是一个位图。
A Bitmap is by definition an array.
位图在定义上是一个数组。
But it's very efficient.
但它非常高效。
A pointer, how many bits you have.
指针，你有多少位？
For a pointer, you have four bytes, like 32 bits at least.
对于一个指针，你有四个字节，至少是32位。
Here you have for one block, you have one bit.
这里的“block”指的是一个块，而“bit”指的是一个比特。
Right.
对的。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
Now let's go back and...
现在让我们回过头来...
So a summary for these fast file systems.
这些快速文件系统的总结是什么？
I now layout.
我现在布局。
If you have a small directory, you can fit all the data of the files in the directory
如果你有一个小目录，你可以将目录中所有文件的数据都放得下。
in the same cylinder.
在同一个汽缸中。
There is no very little six.
没有非常少的六。
And so if the file headers are smaller than the whole blocks, you can obviously fetch
所以，如果文件头部比整个块小，你显然可以获取。
many of those at the same time.
同时有很多人
And the last one, remember that one of the disadvantage of 4.1, it was big reliability,
而最后一个，记住4.1的一个缺点是可靠性较差。
because all the inodes are in one place.
因为所有的inode都在一个位置。
If that place is corrupted, you lost all the information from the entire disk.
如果那个地方被损坏了，你将会丢失整个磁盘上的所有信息。
But here, it's basically if some part is corrupted, and maybe you lose some inodes, the information
但是在这里，基本上如果某个部分损坏了，可能会丢失一些索引节点，信息也会丢失。
about some files, you can never access those files.
关于一些文件，你永远无法访问这些文件。
But many other files, they are still going to be accessible, because their inodes are
但是许多其他文件仍然可以访问，因为它们的inode仍然存在。
going to be intact because they are stored on different places on the disk.
将保持完好，因为它们存储在磁盘的不同位置。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you need to be translated.
So here is another very interesting aspect, is the rotation latency.
所以这里还有一个非常有趣的方面，就是旋转延迟。
We talk about the seek.
我们谈论寻求。
So the block groups are intended to reduce the overhead for the seek time.
所以块组旨在减少寻道时间的开销。
What about rotation latency?
旋转延迟是多少？
Okay.
Sure, I'll do my best to assist you with your translations. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So here is one interesting thing.
这里有一件有趣的事情。
Initially with Unix, a lot of these blocks, you know, the block, a lot of functionality
最初在Unix中，有很多这些块，你知道的，块，很多功能。
of the file system was implemented in the operating system.
文件系统的实现是在操作系统中完成的。
The controllers of the drive, this drive was very simple.
驱动器的控制器，这个驱动器非常简单。
So now the operating system was getting a block.
所以现在操作系统出现了一个阻塞。
Right?
对吗？
So the block, say, and then needs to transfer the data from the block.
所以，块需要传输数据。
But while transferring the data from the block, the head was on top of the next sector.
但是在将数据从块中传输时，磁头位于下一个扇区的顶部。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the text you want to be translated.
And then you don't know, right, and then you are going to miss reading the data from the
然后你不知道，对吧，然后你将无法读取数据。
next sector.
下一个行业。
Right?
对吗？
So basically, think about this.
所以基本上，考虑一下这个。
I want to transfer the data from sectors one by one.
我想逐个将数据从扇区转移。
Assume that the data is on contiguous sectors.
假设数据位于连续的扇区上。
So it's great.
太棒了。
Right?
对吗？
But now the problem is that I read the data from a sector and while I'm transferring the
但是现在的问题是，我正在从一个扇区读取数据，而在我传输数据的同时，
data from the sector to read it, the head is on the next sector.
从该扇区读取的数据，头部位于下一个扇区。
Right?
对吗？
And then I missed that.
然后我错过了那个。
I missed the beginning of the next sector.
我错过了下一个区域的开头。
Right?
对吗？
And then I need to wait for the entire rotation of the disk to get the next sector.
然后我需要等待整个磁盘的旋转，才能获取下一个扇区。
So one original techniques to address this problem, it was when I am writing data on
因此，解决这个问题的一个原始技术是在我写入数据时。
sectors is to interlink, to not write data on subsequent sectors, but skip one sector.
扇区之间的相互连接是为了避免在后续扇区写入数据，而是跳过一个扇区。
So that when I read the data, then I'm reading the data on a sector.
这样当我读取数据时，我实际上是在读取一个扇区的数据。
And while I'm transferring the data from that sector to the operating system, I am not going
而当我将数据从那个扇区传输到操作系统时，我不能
to the next sector.
到下一个行业。
It's fine if I'm skipping it because it doesn't contain the data from the file.
如果我跳过它，因为它不包含文件中的数据，那就没关系。
And by the time the head is over the next sector, which contains the data from the file,
而当磁头移动到下一个扇区时，其中包含了文件的数据，
I am ready to read it.
我已经准备好阅读了。
OK, makes sense.
好的，有道理。
So basically here you overlap the transfer time, right?
所以基本上在这里你重叠了传输时间，对吗？
With the rotation.
带着旋转。
This is pretty cool.
这很酷。
But it turns out that actually the other solution was you just read ahead.
但事实证明，另一个解决方案是提前阅读。
I read a sector and while I am transferring it after that, I'm not sure whether I need
我读取了一个扇区，但在传输之后，我不确定是否需要。
the data from the next sector or not.
下一个部门的数据是否包含在内。
But it's OK.
但没关系。
I'm just assuming that I'm needing it.
我只是假设我需要它。
So I'm going to read ahead.
所以我要提前阅读。
OK.
Sure, I can help you with that. Please go ahead and provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
And if I don't need it, I'm going to discard it.
如果我不需要它，我会把它丢掉。
And I'm just going to buffer it.
然后我只是要缓冲一下。
I just need a buffer to push more data.
我只需要一个缓冲区来存储更多的数据。
OK, so that's another solution.
好的，那就是另一个解决方案。
It's more flexible solution.
这是一个更灵活的解决方案。
And this is actually what today it's used.
这实际上是今天的用法。
And this is implemented mostly in the controllers of the disk.
这主要是在磁盘的控制器中实现的。
The disk has a RAM, has a buffer, if you remember.
这个磁盘有一个RAM，有一个缓冲区，如果你记得的话。
So you read in that buffer, and then you transfer to the operating system.
所以你从那个缓冲区读取，然后传输给操作系统。
Any questions about this?
对此有任何问题吗？
So the first solution is implementing your rewriting, while the second one is implementing
所以第一个解决方案是实施您的重写，而第二个解决方案是实施...
your reading.
你的阅读。
It's a question.
这是一个问题。
No, not really.
不，不是真的。
In both cases, you can think about this optimization for reading.
在这两种情况下，你可以考虑这个优化来进行阅读。
It's again, the problem here is that you read a sector, and then I want to-- I am going
这又是一次，问题在于你读取了一个扇区，然后我想要--我正在去做的是
to send the request for reading the next sector, and the next sector, and the next sector.
发送请求以读取下一个扇区，以及下一个扇区，以及下一个扇区。
So I'm reading the sector, and then I need to transfer the data from the sectors.
所以我正在读取扇区，然后需要将数据从扇区传输出来。
And by the time I am going to issue the request for reading the next sector, the head, it's
而当我准备发出读取下一个扇区的请求时，磁头已经
already over the next sector on the disk.
已经超过了磁盘上的下一个扇区。
Right?
对吗？
Okay, so I'm reading this sector, and then I am-- by the time I am going to issue the
好的，所以我正在阅读这个部门，然后当我准备发出的时候，
request for reading the next sector from the file, the next-- I'm already over the next
请求从文件中读取下一个扇区，下一个——我已经超过了下一个。
sector.
行业。
So I'm going-- so if it happened that actually the sector I want to read is just after the
所以我要去-所以如果碰巧我想阅读的部分就在后面
sector I am reading, then I'm going to miss it.
如果我不读这个部分，我会错过它。
Right?
对吗？
Because I don't get in time the command to read the next sector.
因为我没有及时收到读取下一个扇区的指令。
So therefore, I am going to-- I have to wait all the way for the disk to rotate once to
所以，因此，我要-我必须等待光盘旋转一圈。
read the next sector.
读取下一个扇区。
So what this first optimization says that I am reading a sector, and now I am transferring
所以这个第一个优化是说我正在读取一个扇区，现在正在传输。
and giving some time before I get the next command.
并且在我收到下一个指令之前给我一些时间。
And if I get the next command, then I am going to know-- I'm going to be close to this next
如果我得到下一个指令，那么我就会知道——我就会接近下一个目标。
sector after I skip one.
跳过一个后的部门。
Okay?
好的。
So if I want to contiguously in this mode to have maximized performance, I need to interleave
所以如果我想在这种模式下连续地获得最大化的性能，我需要交错使用。
the sectors when I write them.
当我写它们时，指的是各个行业。
So when I read them, I am going to read once, and while I am transferring and getting command
所以当我阅读它们时，我会读一遍，同时我会进行转移和接收指令。
for reading the next sector, I have enough time.
读取下一个扇区，我有足够的时间。
So I am ready to read the next sector.
所以我准备好阅读下一个部分了。
This makes sense?
这有意义吗？
How big does a track buffer usually need to be to store the entire track?
通常，一个音轨缓冲区需要多大才能存储整个音轨？
That's a very good question.
这是一个非常好的问题。
So you can read ahead the entire track.
所以你可以提前阅读整个赛道。
I don't know on top of my head what is how much.
我脑海中不知道是多少。
Yeah, I'll probably-- I'll try to get back to you, but I assume a few tens of megabytes
是的，我可能会尽量回复你，但我估计会有几十兆字节。
depending on the disk.
取决于硬盘。
But yeah.
但是，是的。
So Gilbert, did I answer your question?
所以，Gilbert，我回答了你的问题吗？
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and translate any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the text you would like me to translate.
So it's again, remember that the disks and this controller do a lot of things under the
所以，再次提醒一下，这些磁盘和控制器在下面做了很多事情。
hood, right?
对，是帽子，对吗？
Like, remember we did last time, we learned about C-scan and other scheduling algorithms.
好的，记得上次我们学习了C-scan和其他调度算法。
You should order the request so therefore you reduce the six-time rotation latency.
你应该对请求进行排序，从而减少六倍的旋转延迟。
Okay.
好的。
So the pros of 4.2, you have efficient storage for both small and large files.
所以4.2的优点是，您可以高效地存储小型和大型文件。
And this is because you have these direct blocks, indirect block pointers, and double
这是因为你有这些直接块、间接块指针和双重块。
indirect and triple indirect.
间接和三重间接。
So you can accommodate both small files and large files.
所以你可以同时容纳小文件和大文件。
You have locality for both small and large files to try to do that because you try to
你尝试着对小文件和大文件都进行本地化，以便实现这一目标。
store them within the same block group or cylinder group.
将它们存储在同一个块组或柱组中。
And you also try to-- you have the locality between the metadata and data because the
而且你也试着——你在元数据和数据之间有局部性，因为
metadata that is inodes, we try to store them on the same block group where the files themselves
元数据即索引节点，我们尝试将它们存储在与文件本身相同的块组中。
are stored.
存储在哪里。
We didn't talk about this when we say non-defragmentation is necessary.
我们在说非碎片整理是必要的时候没有讨论过这个。
Non-defragmentation is necessary here because we have the bitmap.
非碎片整理在这里是必要的，因为我们有位图。
In what happens with-- and I remember that when I used it a long time ago.
关于这个问题，我记得很久以前我用过它。
When you use FAT and when you-- or this Microsoft, early Microsoft operating systems and the file
当你使用FAT时，或者说在早期的微软操作系统和文件系统中使用FAT。
systems, what you have from time to time, you need to defragment the disk.
系统，你时不时需要对磁盘进行碎片整理。
Defragment the disk, what meant is this to rewrite the information from the disk so the
磁盘碎片整理，指的是重新将磁盘上的信息进行重写，以便提高磁盘的读写速度和性能。
files are more contiguously stored.
文件存储更加连续。
Because the disk was fragmented.
因为磁盘被碎片化了。
As you delete disks, as you delete files and you write more files, it's more and more fragmented,
当你删除磁盘、删除文件并写入更多文件时，它会变得越来越碎片化。
meaning that the data of the files is stored more and more randomly.
这意味着文件的数据存储越来越随机。
The blocks are more and more randomly.
这些方块越来越随机。
And from time to time, you do defragmentation.
有时候，你会进行碎片整理。
So you are going to try again to rewrite the files.
所以你打算再次尝试重写这些文件。
So to move the blocks around, so to speak, so that the files are stored on contiguous
因此，可以说，为了移动这些块，使文件存储在连续的位置上。
blocks and the performance will be much better.
块和性能会更好。
Here is not really necessary because I told you about these heuristics in which you try
这里并不是真正必要的，因为我已经告诉过你关于这些启发式的事情，其中你尝试
to find a large bunch of free blocks for large files to store the data.
寻找一大堆用于存储数据的大文件的免费块。
The cost is inefficient for tiny files.
这个成本对于小文件来说是低效的。
It's a little bit unfair because it's not-- you still fundamentally need a block to store--
这有点不公平，因为你仍然基本上需要一个块来存储--
so you need to have storage, it's a block.
所以你需要有存储空间，它是一个块。
So even if you have one byte, you still are going to read or write an entire block, which
所以即使你只有一个字节，你仍然会读取或写入整个块，这
is 40 kilobytes.
是40千字节。
And in addition, also you need an inode for this data block.
而且，你还需要为这个数据块分配一个inode。
Most of the file systems will have this big advantage.
大多数文件系统都会有这个巨大的优势。
And inefficient encoding when a file is mostly contiguous on the disk, this basically says
当文件在磁盘上大部分是连续的时候，使用低效的编码方式，这基本上意味着
that you know you are going to have this bitmap to tell you what the blocks are.
你知道你将要有这个位图来告诉你块的情况。
And if you have, you have one bit for each block.
如果你有的话，每个块都有一个位。
But for instance, if the file is contiguous, stored on the disk, then you need only two
但是例如，如果文件是连续存储在磁盘上的，那么你只需要两个
pieces of information, what is the beginning, the pointer to the first block, and the pointer
信息的组成部分，什么是起始点，指向第一个块的指针，以及指针。
to the last block, right?
到最后一个街区，对吗？
Because everything in between is contiguous.
因为中间的一切都是连续的。
This is what it means it's inefficient encoding when files is mostly contiguous on the disk.
这意味着当文件在磁盘上大部分是连续的时候，它的编码是低效的。
And still in order to avoid this defragmentation, you need to have this kind of sprees space
而且为了避免这种碎片化，你需要有这种类型的空闲空间。
on the disk.
在磁盘上。
So you cannot allocate the entire 100% of the disk space.
所以你不能分配整个100%的磁盘空间。
You need to leave around 10, 20%.
你需要留下大约10、20%。
Okay, Linux is pretty similar.
好的，Linux相当相似。
You have 12 direct pointers, like in our previous examples, if you remember, when I was a little
你有12个直接指针，就像我们之前的例子一样，如果你还记得的话，当时我还小。
kid, I was confused between 12 and 10.
孩子，我在12和10之间感到困惑。
In this case, you have 12.
在这种情况下，你有12个。
And the other thing you can configure is the size of the blocks to be different sizes,
而另一件您可以配置的事情是块的大小可以是不同的尺寸，
right?
对吗？
You can have one kilobyte, two kilobytes, four kilobytes, eight kilobytes, and so forth.
你可以有一千字节、两千字节、四千字节、八千字节，以此类推。
It's again, you don't have in the same system, blocks of different sizes, but when you configure
再次强调，你在同一个系统中没有不同尺寸的块，但是当你进行配置时，
the system to start with, you can choose different blocks sizes.
系统起始时，您可以选择不同的块大小。
And this X2 and X3 are different versions of Linux in terms of particular or disk layout.
而这个X2和X3是在特定或磁盘布局方面不同的Linux版本。
You also have journaling.
你也可以写日记。
We are going to talk about journaling later, but it's a particular way to store the files
我们稍后会讨论日志记录，但这是一种特殊的文件存储方式。
to provide fault tolerance.
提供容错性。
Okay, we'll talk more about that.
好的，我们会更详细地讨论这个。
And other than that, it's the same kind of organization here.
除此之外，这里的组织方式与其他地方相同。
You have, these are the pointers in the group descriptor table.
你有，这些是组描述符表中的指针。
You have pointers to the blocks.
你有指向这些块的指针。
In each blocks, you have inot tables.
在每个区块中，你有不同的表格。
And then the inot tables are going to go, going to go to directories.
然后inot表将被转移到目录中。
This is how the directories are organized in EX2-3.
这是EX2-3中目录的组织方式。
Okay, it's setting up.
好的，正在设置中。
Hard links.
硬链接。
Okay, sorry.
好的，抱歉。
So here, we remember last time, we looked through this directory structure and the directory
所以在这里，我们记得上次我们浏览了这个目录结构和目录。
structure, it's an ROG.
结构，它是一台ROG。
And what you have, typically what you can do in Unix, you can have a different, you
而你所拥有的，通常在Unix中可以做的事情，你可以有一个不同的，
can have another hard link, it's called hard link, another link to the same file, right?
可以有另一个硬链接，它被称为硬链接，指向同一文件的另一个链接，对吗？
You can have the same file, which is basically, you can have two names for that file and these
你可以拥有同一个文件，也就是说，你可以为该文件设置两个名称，这样
names can appear in different directories.
名字可以出现在不同的目录中。
When do you want to do that?
你想什么时候做那件事？
Well, obviously when I want to share a file from different directories, right?
嗯，显然我是指当我想要从不同的目录共享文件时，对吧？
And I want to appear to be local to that directory.
我想要看起来像是属于那个目录的本地人。
It's like, for instance, library files or things like that.
就像，比如说，库文件或者类似的东西。
And in this case, again, I'm going to have pointers, the same, two different file names
在这种情况下，我会再次使用指针，同样是两个不同的文件名。
are going to point to the same file.
将指向同一个文件。
And in the inode, I'm going to maintain a reference count.
在inode中，我将维护一个引用计数。
Why I need that?
为什么我需要那个？
Because only when all the references to the same inode, to the same underlying file are
因为只有当所有对同一个inode的引用指向同一个底层文件时，才能
removed, I can remove the file.
已删除，我可以删除这个文件。
In addition, I have also soft links.
此外，我还有软链接。
The soft links provide the same kind of behavior.
软链接提供了相同类型的行为。
It's again, they are used to create another entry in my current directory to a file which
这是再次发生了，它们被用来在我的当前目录中创建另一个指向文件的条目。
exists in a different directory.
存在于不同的目录中。
But this is symbolic link or soft link.
但这是一个符号链接或软链接。
In this case, it's actually a symbolic link, it's another entry in the directory, which
在这种情况下，实际上是一个符号链接，它是目录中的另一个条目，它
basically it's about, it has a file name, the new file name, and then it's linked to
基本上，它涉及到一个文件名、新的文件名，然后与之关联。
the destination file name.
目标文件名。
So it's a symbolic link, just an entry, just something you write in your directory, which
所以它是一个符号链接，只是一个条目，只是你在目录中写的东西，它
basically links the file name, the new file name, with the destination file name, the
基本上将文件名、新文件名和目标文件名链接在一起，
one which I want to link.
一个我想要链接的。
And in this particular case, though, if the destination file name is removed, the openings
而在这种特殊情况下，如果目标文件名被删除，那么打开的
are filed using the symbolic link name, it can fail.
如果使用符号链接名称进行归档，可能会失败。
Because there is no one under the hood to keep the reference counting how many other
由于引用计数没有人在后台进行维护，无法知道有多少其他的引用。
file names are pointing to the same file.
文件名指向同一个文件。
But this is easier to implement.
但是这样更容易实施。
So this is what it is.
这就是它的样子。
And you can create both command line, the symbolic links, also hard links, also you
可以创建命令行、符号链接和硬链接。
can have a system call to programmatically manipulate the symbolic links.
可以使用系统调用来以编程方式操作符号链接。
So let's look here as an example, and we are close to the end of the lecture, about what
让我们以这里作为一个例子，我们已经接近讲座的结束，谈论一下关于什么。
happens under the hood.
发生在引擎盖下。
And let's say we want to access this file staff.txt and the path name is home/cs on
并且假设我们想要访问这个文件staff.txt，路径名是home/cs。
c2 and then is the name of the file staff.txt.
c2然后是文件名staff.txt。
So first of all, we need to start from the root.
首先，我们需要从根源开始。
So you need to have the ID number of the root and say that's the position 2.
所以你需要有根的ID号，并说这是第2个位置。
And this one is going, obviously, is going to have here an inode.
这个显然会有一个inode。
The inode is going to contain a pointer to the data.
inode将包含指向数据的指针。
And this data in this case contains the directory data, directory entries.
这个案例中的数据包含目录数据、目录条目。
Remember a directory entry maps a file to a file number.
记住，目录条目将文件映射到文件号。
Let's assume that the file number is 8086.
让我们假设文件号是8086。
So now, and this is what you have in memory, what you have here down, it's in memory.
所以现在，这是你记忆中的内容，你在这里写下的，都在记忆中。
Now you read the block 8086, right?
现在你读的是8086块，对吗？
And what do you get there?
你在那里能得到什么？
You are going to get the I number of the file.
你将获得文件的I号码。
You have the I number and the I number for this, the subdirectory cs162.
你有I号和I号，用于这个子目录cs162。
And you are going to get from that I number, you are going to get data in that directory.
你将会从那个编号中得到数据，你将会在那个目录中获取数据。
And data in the directory is going to maintain the entry and mapping between cs162 and its
目录中的数据将维护cs162和其之间的条目和映射。
I number, let's say 732.
我是一个数字，比如说732。
So you go to 732 now with the I number and you are going now finally to get all the information
所以你现在带着I号码去732，最终你将获得所有的信息。
which is in cs162 directory, which is also you have file staff.txt here.
这是在cs162目录中，你还在这里有一个文件staff.txt。
And once you read the data in the directory, you are going to find the mapping between
并且一旦你读取目录中的数据，你将会找到它们之间的映射关系。
staff.txt and its I number.
staff.txt和它的I号。
So the number now is 9909.
所以现在的数字是9909。
So finally, I have 9909, which is the I number of staff.txt.
所以最后，我有了9909，这是staff.txt的I号。
Now I can start reading the data from staff.txt.
现在我可以开始读取staff.txt文件中的数据了。
This may require to read additional blocks before I get to the data blocks.
这可能需要在读取数据块之前读取额外的块。
If this file is large and we need to have single indirected or double indirect or triple
如果这个文件很大，我们需要使用单间接、双间接或三间接。
indirect data blocks.
间接数据块。
This is pretty much what happens.
这基本上就是发生的事情。
And this is the data blocks from the file.
这是文件中的数据块。
And that's pretty much it.
这就是大致的内容。
So let's stop here and we'll continue next time.
那么我们就到这里停下来，下次再继续。
Oh, so here the question is that what if there was also a file in /.home called cs162?
哦，所以问题是，如果在/.home目录下也有一个名为cs162的文件，会怎么样呢？
I'm going to answer this question.
我要回答这个问题。
So basically if it was in home another file, that will be cs162.txt.
所以基本上，如果它在家里的另一个文件中，那将是cs162.txt。
Also it will have a different extension.
还有，它将有一个不同的扩展名。
So the file system will differentiate.
所以文件系统会有所区分。
If the file system would have exactly the same name as a directory, that cannot happen.
如果文件系统的名字与一个目录完全相同，那是不可能发生的。
You cannot have a file name and a directory of the same name in the same directory.
在同一个目录中，你不能同时拥有相同名称的文件名和目录名。
You can try it.
你可以试试看。
You cannot create it.
你不能创建它。
You will get an error.
你会收到一个错误。
Okay.
Sure, I will translate your Chinese text into English and any non-Chinese text into Chinese. Please provide me with the content you would like to be translated.
With this, thank you and I'll see you next time.
好的，谢谢你，下次再见。
[ Silence ]
[沉默]